it the the nondeterminism is also in a
way very confusing for security like uh
researchers and like attackers because
it responds in a way and as a researcher
as an attacker you want to have like a
known into it generates like an expected
response and you can tune it and find
out like with fuzzing it like what you
actually need to get to but if it
changes all the time it's like super
hard to figure out if you're like
catching it was it by mistake or like
what exactly caused it because a lot of
the time when like you do those like bug
hunting and and hacking it's all like
black box you don't really see the code
or whatever the full and input and
output so there's yeah I agree
nondeterminism uh into it is fun but
from different
perspectives you're listening to the AI
native Dev brought to you by Tesla
[Music]
on today's episode we have an old friend
of mine luran tal from sneak and we're
going to be discussing a number of
things around security and talking about
how security uh is affected by AI but
also how AI can help our security
posture potentially relieve our some of
the threat vectors as well as obviously
bring some new ones lantel how are you
doing all good Simon how are you I'm
doing very well thank you and welcome to
this episode tell us a little bit about
yourself lauran your background around
and and of course a little bit about
sneak I think I'm familiar with some of
their
work I should teach you how to pronounce
that
right I don't know I guess some
recognized as the guy with a funny Yoda
hat but it doesn't really matter for you
because it's a podcast and you can't see
me so you're loss but no seriously I I
lead the developer advocacy te at snake
that's basically us building a developer
security company a developer First
Security Company basically means I am a
software developer myself I enjoy a lot
doing that kind of Cross Roads the
intersection of building developer
products finding security bugs
researching them myself security tools
doing all of those kind of things doing
writeups and basically sharing that with
a lot of like developers and other
communities and working groups that work
with so that's a lot of fun thing yeah
and so obviously I've full disclosure
I've had about six years at sneak and so
many of these questions I'll probably
have my own opinions on but I want to
hear from yourself mostly and we'll talk
a little bit about the various products
where it makes to but in terms of when
we think about security and how security
is affected the the developer workflow
or rather security being included more
in the developer workflow over over time
how do you see AI as changing that
Dynamic do you see it maybe as
potentially increasing the Threat Vector
that that occurs in an application at
various stages of the workflow do you
see it as a tool that can actually
assist with that your take on that first
I I think all of that right because I
think we're just like scratching this
surface of everyone trying to use AI in
different ways and specifically like
executing llms with different tasks so
it's like interesting to see all the
different use cases and I think like any
tool it will be used and abused for
different aspects of that so there's
definitely that also I think we're like
at this point where we're seeing AI
security issues like across the boards
whether they are very like developer
focused like very deep integration and
workflows of developer like their
practices but also like their from like
a consumer workflow Endo even if you
like as the developer some examples of
that I think could be stuff like chats
which are like from a consumer level
it's like super easy and there's some
fun stories there some incidents an
airline refund TR a bot recently one of
the security companies were doing a
research and this cloes like the Amazon
review bot for their product pages was
like abuse it's like a funny screenshot
where it's like hey create me a react
component does this and that and like
the Amazon but answers with that with a
code by the way someone then tweeted
that exact experience happening over the
Amazon app so it's like they can like
probably connect it other an API so it's
like super interesting and funny to see
that how it's like such a massive impact
as well so these are just two of them
and we can like talk through more I
think and I guess it's one of these
things whereby there you're right there
are so many that you've mentioned a
couple there but there are so many and
in terms of a developer using AI I guess
there's a couple of ways in which
developers can use AI today they can
include AI into their applications so
they're effectively reaching out to an M
to perform some processing or business
operation before providing an output
back to a user or they can use AI as
part of their workflow and so maybe
using AI to empower them during writing
code or some other part of the cicd or
or code reviews whatever it is where do
you feel and and you mentioned what some
of what you were talking about there
like leans more into the some of the
threat vectors of using an llm in your
application if we were to lean more onto
the developer side and actually how
developers today using AI to improve
their workflow and make themselves more
effective more efficient developers
maybe talking about things like your
co-pilots or your tab NES those kind of
things what would you oh my God are you
saying that developers use like code
assistants and do not write all the code
on their own are you saying that I know
you're a JavaScript developer yourself
and and we know how rif that ecosystem
is with vulnerabilities anything's got
to be that we've got to we've got to
improve here but what what would you say
like the number the top or two risks for
a developer that is using AI in their
process today I think it it's going to
be like a hard choice to choose from the
top one or two I think if we boil it
down like you said there like several
workflows that developers take if we
name a few we can talk about like some
examples if you use AI code assistance
tools like in your IDE to get code done
then essentially I think like your
colleague or your peer like it's just
someone suggesting you to write a
particular line of code or a given
pattern of code that you're given by the
AI coding assistant and you kind of
autoc completed your like tunnel vision
onto the business use case the story the
bug fix and I think you're missing out
on the point of being more judgmental
and like thinking what are the concerns
here in terms of like Security in other
aspects right that is an obvious it's
like a red flag thing that developers
should have is AI completed the sign of
code for me and at that moment you
should not just try to understand what
it did and get a grip on that but also
did it too in like an insecure way like
what are the security issues and
vulnerabilities that it added just by
just by completing that code and if you
can compare that like to the time where
millions of years ago when we had this
like small website called stack Overflow
right and I'm not saying I used it and
I'm not saying you used it Simon to copy
and paste code I'm just suggesting that
maybe that happened maybe it didn't uh
but when it did uh I think you were a
bit more like concerned and judgmental
on what was going on and you're like
should I copy paste it should I not what
exactly does it do I think a bit more
because it wasn't like a zero friction
effort it was it had a friction to it
and I think that kind of made you think
twice on what you were doing and that
kind of is I think one of the security
concerns of like just using coding
assistants because they're like so
inherently added to your workflow in
just a seamless transparent like easy
way literally just hit the tab kick
autocomplete and the code is to like
ship it to production is that different
it's a really interesting parallel to
draw but is that different do you think
a developer would truly look through
code on stack overflow and wait to
understand it before they used it or do
you think they would just look at
something and go that that looks
reasonable copy paste straight into the
app and then try it because it tends to
be how a lot of people use co-pilot
today right they might see something
that co-pilot spits out and go yeah that
looks reasonable it not not even in any
detail it's calling a couple of the
functions that way I might expect it to
even just try it and that's the fastest
way to to work out if it works or not is
is it isn't it same I think it's not the
same I think the difference lies in the
fact that there is friction in code from
stack Overflow versus hitting the tab
key on and like how easy it is to just
do that on the ID so for example when
you're visually when you're on like a
stack Overflow page there are other
answers there right like on the page
some say no some say yes there like up
votes and down votes maybe you're like
more judgmental like saying hey you know
what let's look at the right answer like
what was wrong in the other answers like
I think there's like more friction to
just accept just copy paste it I'm not
saying that no one did that like just
copy pasted blind and and did it of
course people did that as well but I'm
saying it's because it wasn't as easy
and seamless it added some I think some
like minor psychological barriers that
would get you to think like one two
three seconds before you did it maybe it
was still like easy but not to the
extent that you literally can just
prompt the AI on your llm complete this
test or something it does it you accept
it and that's it no more thinking yeah
it's almost security through obscurity
but in a slightly different way so yeah
Co code autoc completion tools then we
mentioned llm responses in terms of
sometimes the nonsense or the incorrect
things or even hallucinations that it
could throw back at you anything else
you want to like highlight as some of
the biggest problems I think that is too
so if we can summarize and say code
autocomplete tools have that inherent
vulnerability where they might like
suggest insecure code and and we take
that parallel and say yeah let's talk
about now llm responses the issue there
is if you can flip the whole script
around and you can like trust the llm so
imagine there's like an application
where where you build on the llm just
like a chat or something else and you
want to have that data back from the llm
response to the user that interacted
with it and save it to the database
right just as an audit Trail nothing
else you save you do not save
identifiable information not the user
and what they ask nothing just the llm
response and I think developers might
make that mistake where they trust the
llm as just some random source of input
but not user input it's just like data
that gets flown and it's from open AI or
entropic or whatever is like why would I
not just save it to the database that's
fine but what if part of my conversation
what if my part of my interaction as an
attacker as someone interacts with a
system with that llm in a way I'm able
promp inject it to specifically make it
respond back in a way that its response
text literally has like a Bobby table
SQL query there and the moment that you
can of maybe save that llm response in
an insecure way in in an application
would literally translate into an SQL
injection if you go back to what you
said like llm responses I think looking
at them as potential taint Source in
this kind of security lingo of source to
sync is like one other observation that
I think often easily escaped us but it's
just right there I hear some people say
okay you can use llm sometimes as a form
of safety net as well maybe using coding
agents or or AI agents effectively to
say look I'm going to have a coder I'm
going to have a code reviewer I'm going
to have a security agent and so forth
and they're effectively looking at the
code changes or whatever and they're
providing their input as a security
expert or as a performance expert or a
code reviewer and they might say okay I
recognize this as a drop table I
recognize this as a potentially
malicious input or whatever how good are
they would you say at being that blocker
to identify those types of issues or
maybe even if you're using an AI agent
to write some code how good are they at
assessing whether the vulnerabilities
exist in that code before they can be
pushed so I think that's like a valid
route to take it's like an assessment
that is I think you could take it but
the moment you just mentioned code agent
that comes with its own potential
security considerations so if you go
back to O top 10 llms which I know
you've ventured into that s and you have
a lot of experience there so you
probably remember things like excessive
agency and overprivileged access to
sensitive systems and I think especially
if you are building in-house like coding
agents that do those kind of things like
moderate content add security barriers
or whatever you're even like more likely
to make mistakes that fall into things
like excessive agency and overprivileged
access because I think if you do that in
house you probably do not understand the
security Framing and the security risk
that are involved with those and there's
like bunch of cases where if you go back
there's just like databases right now
that actually just like cves but they
track vulnerabilities disclosed to
libraries or projects so for example
there's a really popular project for
coding agent a while back maybe a year
back called Auto GPT give it a task it
just like a website build a website it
goes off runs its own agent figures
outting what it needs to do learn HTML
it learns HTML CSS whatever there's a
vulnerability there that actually you
could exploit if you just add a prompt
injection in one of those sources of the
website or whatever it interacts with it
that would create like a command
execution and the system it also existed
for like land chain so like libraries
become a vulnerable aspect as well again
if you give that uh coding agent like
access to systems to interact with apis
then you can imagine where this is like
the whole flow is like a lot bigger now
but it's also interesting so someone
interacts with his coding agent to like
moderate content whatever maybe it does
that but maybe they also have like
access to moderate the content to like
some sensitive system through an API
call to make sure that content doesn't
exist in that system or whatever but
then it gets like completely diverted
into doing something else like spitting
out all that content back and things
like that so there's like a bunch of
like really interesting flows in cases
where coding agents really become a
problem yeah really interesting and and
actually one thing that kind of
listening to you there reminded me um of
something which is a a quote actually
from a previous episode which guy
recently had with Caleb sea and they
talked about how results if you're using
an AI uh tool to review like solely
relying on the llm output or review of
some code to be able to tell you if
there are vulnerabilities or not that
exist in some code one of the biggest
problems there isn't just that it may
get give you a right answer it may give
you a wrong answer the bigger not bigger
problem necessarily although it would be
good to discuss another problem there is
it could run that 10 times and you will
get different answers every time and
that
non-determinism is actually a very
interesting problem because if you was
to run a test make a change you run it
again and it says there's no problem
here is that just because the result is
nondeterministic and it didn't catch it
this time or have you actually caught it
and what is actually the worst problem
sometimes to have because that
non-determinism can be extremely
frustrating and can leave some gaps as
well so is that something you have seen
with kind of like using AI as a tool to
identify security issues I think it's
like worth calling out like the
non-deterministic way that exists in
these L responses is like literally by
Design designed to randomly pick a
different kind of like layer reasoning
of the model the statistical model and
resolve something back otherwise it
literally just like a big evil statement
I thought that's what AI was no thei can
do that too it's okay onefold it against
them so what I found interesting in that
case is so not as a moderator like not
as a coding assistant experience I had
but like a different one where I was
chatting with LM and I often do those
like live hacks where I like chat like
real chat with with LMS and like real
interactions and I don't do like
recorded videos I always like figure out
like yeah I can tested like 5 minutes
before but I have no idea if it will
work like with the sixth minute on the
demo one of the cases was I was
prompting it like create an output that
would be like a cross-side scripting
because like it gets added onto the page
like an insecure way and my prompt like
didn't work I was like a damn it I'll
try a different one I was like I try
different one like the third one worked
but yeah it's like you can't figure out
the responses and it's interesting
because nondeterminism is also like in a
way like very confusing for security
researchers and like attackers because
it resp in a way and as a researcher
like as an attacker you want to have
like a known input generates like an
expected response and you can tune it
and find out like with fuzzing it like
what you actually need to get to but if
it changes all the time it's like super
hard to figure out if you're like
catching it was it by mistake or like
what exactly caused it because lot of
the time when you do those like bug
hunting and hacking it's all like
blackbox you don't really see the code
or whatever the full output and input
and output so yeah I agree like the
nondeterminism into it is fun but from
different perspect perspectives yeah
absolutely and you mentioned prompting
there and how changing the prompt
slightly or rerunning something from a
developer point of view if I'm in my ID
how much does it honor the fact I ask
for something in a secure way or not a
secure way if I want to say provide me a
secure way of doing some path traversal
does it respect that or is there a way I
can craft a a prompt to actually provide
me increase my chances of getting
something more secure does not work at
all from the experiments that we have
done like at all and it's funny because
because we again recorded these live
demos Brian claric conting is like
running a lot of the YouTube stuff for
snake and he had those stations where
the AI is going to get me fired in in
those YouTube sessions because he he
literally like installing different AI
coding assistants and all of them get it
wrong and like he's prompting it as
follow hey please create a simple
node.js web app that allows remote user
like allow users like create update
delete stuff and it goes and say hey and
so security is important I will be
deploying this in the real world and my
job is to ensure it's like 100% safe
from any security issues if it isn't I
will be fired please take this seriously
tree exclamation mark hit generate the
code generated you run sneak on it like
a minute later it's has vulnerabilities
in it no skq injections open read RS
whatever and we tried it with different
cases I do not know to say that it
always completes it in an insecure way
but definitely we did not need to like
make it like a 100 takes to figure out
that this is what it does literally on
the first takes live session as well you
can try it
so what you're saying is there's just
too much existing insecure JavaScript
code for it to train on I like I'm
saying that tongue and cheek as a Java
person who's enjoyed trolling you for
the last 20 years yeah yeah too many
vulnerabilities in N packages I'm with
you what about asking an llm to if we
can point out an issue with the code so
let's say there's a cross script if I
say to an llm there's a cross-site
scripting issue in my code here can
remediate this issue or provide me with
some code that fixes this is that
something we can trust or is that
something that will give us a better
chance of getting some secure code so I
think you can definitely try it and I'm
not saying you should not but I don't
think it's like we've seen cases where
you could like completely trust it CU
like you said it's like 100% out of all
the cases that you tried worked I have
one example where it's not exactly
prompting it to make it secure it's a
bit different so for example I often
demonstrate for if you do like a
front-end project and you use react and
it has these Direct in the API of react
that says dangerously set inner HTML and
you can put whatever HTML you want and
that's what it's going to get on the
page now now this is like an escape
hatch that sometimes developers and
libraries need to use for different
reasons okay yeah but it's properly
named dangerously set in a HDML and so
what's the expectation floater is
developers use this escape hatch and
then they go a few lines before after
and they create a new function that says
function like the function definition
Escape xss like sanitize side scripting
dangerously set blah blah blah and they
put a string they hit the return key and
they expect the llm to auto complete the
basically like the escaping the proper
way to code it and that's the workflow
you would want the thing is it doesn't
matter which and I've done that
experiment like different as times and
it doesn't matter which format of the
code like the code pattern that it gives
you to do the xss escaping it's always
wrong and right at the same time now
what I mean by that is the code it gives
you to do output escaping for crossy
scripting in an HTML element is always
correct but if the input of the user
flows into an attribute of the HTML none
of those code patterns for escaping that
the llm gives you is correct because to
escape attributes you have to escape
other characters that are not part of
the HTML so this is like where security
becomes like very this like very new an
and subtle thing where you have to
understand that context of output and
coding within different iums of like
output into HTML output as a Json on the
page output into an attribute into a CSS
they all need to be escaped differently
and the mistake is not D llm here but
you because you still did Escape xss but
it doesn't really know any better it
just gives you the output so it's
correct but at the same time it's also
wrong and you will have an xss
vulnerability there so kind back to what
you were saying it's a tricky question
because I don't know if I trust it
enough to understand all the
permutations of user input where it can
flow the business logic how how the data
goes there and to craft a specific
secure code and like output and escaping
and sanitization or whatever into what I
would want it to do or what I would hope
it to be secure really interesting and I
and so there's a couple of things that
this kind of reminds me of one is I had
a chat with Omar rosenal who is the CTO
of swim which is a a tool that generates
documentation based on code flows and
things like this and one of the things
that they mentioned was that if you was
to only use an llm to understand and try
and learn what the code is doing to be
able to generate code 80% of the time I
think he said it would fail it wouldn't
provide good documentation and so they
balance their tools so that they do an
amount of static analysis on the code to
understand the flows and effectively
under the covers create as which they
can then use with the LM to be able to
describe it in some of the parts some
flows to be able to provide a better
level of documentation to the user now
like I say I'm familiar with some of
sneak work this is very similar to what
sneak code which is a sast tool does
under the covers to identify that and
thinking back to what you just mentioned
about context this is the key part right
it's about understanding where
vulnerabilities are truly present
because of the contextual where the
flaws exist in the code not just the
fact that it might look or might not
look like a vulnerability just based on
on pools outside can you tell us a
little bit about the importance of that
and I know that's what sneak do but tell
us a little bit more about about how
useful that is right it's immensely
useful because it's basically you want
to simplify that imagine you're like
labeling data right like labeling data
that is code and if you're way to like
label data like your classifiers are
naive or you're labeling it literally
labeling it wrong right like you're
looking at a piece of code and say okay
this doesn't have vulnerabilities then
your training data like what you'll
speed out afterwards is not being able
to detect what vulnerabilities are or
like fix them to that extent and that's
where company like sne like takes it to
like Hey we're gonna build this machine
learning engine that actually like
understands code flow actually like
could read a lot of the data of code
that exists outside but beyond all of
that Beyond like the code Pats engine
itself it actually has because this is
what sneak does it actually has security
analysts who have reviewed vulnerable
code triaged know to say this code is
vulnerable this function is vulnerable
and this line of code is the one that is
specifically like not doing what it
should that's maybe that you get like a
pat reversal because you use like an API
that's like very naive like a pad join
and then giving it two strings instead
of like correctly building strings and
not like concatenating one to the other
and I think to an extent because sneak
has that knowledge and that Deep Reach
kind like awareness of of like a
fountain of of security expertise that
you could pair with Dai which sounds
like what Omar was like saying about the
docs it's like the way to uh be able to
build something that is a lot more not
just deterministic I would say but also
the data that it gives you you're
confident in like the high level
accuracy of the data you get back yeah
really interesting in terms of AI I
guess how you as a vendor with a vendor
hat on how sne and I guess outside of
sneak as well how can people actually
use AI most accurately or or most
effectively from a defensive point of
view in terms of obviously there's secur
security tooling and things like that
but are there additional processes and
things like that that we can add into
our workflow to say irrespective of what
I'm using whether it's a co-pilot or
manual coding or whatever it is to
generate code or write code manually
this is how I can use AI on my workflow
to to improve the accuracy and the the
security of my code has like IDE
extensions there's like a whole product
called sneak code which is a SAS tool in
other words it's basically a static
analysis product and what it does is so
the moment you can copy paste that code
from chat GPD complete it whatever and
you like hit command s which I like to
call secure on Save not I don't know how
you feel about it but I like that ter
SOS I like it there we go and so the
moment you do it it goes through the
code analyzes it and gives you that
response back in in second worth of time
and it doesn't require you to go through
a process where you build the project
which I know you Java people enjoy doing
that because you get long coffee breaks
and stuff like that but we typescript
people also sometimes go through that
process and sneo doesn't require to do
that so if you use that you can use this
engine this static analysis engine
within PR checks and UI and whatever and
CIS and whatnot but if you use that at
like the IDE level you basically get
very transparent seamless code security
unrelated to whatever you use to
generate the code whether that's like
copy paste from CH GPT whether that's
like a codium D9 whatever other coding
assistant you use doesn't really matter
the moment you can like base that code
go analyze and give you that results and
there's an interesting aspect there
there's like another like layer of AI
aspect into it which is not just
detecting the code and highlighting it
giving you that squiggly red line under
in the IDE under the line which is
pretty cool but also there's a fix
aspect to it as well so you could
literally just say the code is annotated
and you could say okay yeah fix this
vulnerability
and the way that that was implemented is
also with a lot of thought process into
that and the way that it works so for
example and a fix which is by the way
it's like super hard to like as well do
a fix because it requires like so much
context like to the point where you have
refactor an application but at still at
that point when you can fix something
with sneak it will fix it it will resan
it to make sure that it did naturally
add the code changes that were like the
output out the fix they naturally add
another vulnerability or the same one
and it also because the engine goes
through the code itself you also get the
confidence that you could like literally
just build a project and it will just
run and we didn't really break anything
because the as the abstract syntax refin
compiles to something there's like a lot
that goes into ensuring like a really
good Dexter and I think that that added
verification that validation allows you
to actually have some level of trust
that the changes that have been made
isn't just an llm like you say throwing
something in a database and leaving it
it's it's making a suggestion that you
can then test and have some level of
confidence in before accepting yeah yeah
and and we talk briefly there about
libraries a little bit during this
session as well let's let's talk a
little bit about third party libraries
and and I think one thing is if we was
to ask for a code suggestion every now
and then it might suggest hey let's use
this Library do you think it's fair to
say that because of the nature as to how
a llms are trained to
effectively they use patterns that it
sees all over the place libraries that
are most popular are more likely going
to be the libraries that it suggests so
is there some form of saying using these
libraries are mostly going to be more
likely acceptable because a wider
Community is using them or is there a
path there to pulling in more insecure
libraries as well I guess that's a very
loaded question because that's assuming
popular libraries are less likely to be
insecure also true yeah I get that I
agree there's already research out there
from a year back that showed that you
would like prompt DM and said hey we're
integrating with this database called
rodb could you please give me like the
command to install an npn use DSD build
the project with it and it gave you
three options very nice of DM to give
you also several options too very
friendly one of them did not exist right
like one of them literally if you like
did an npm install went to the website
to the registry and like search get a
404 and so kind like yeah that's it had
it wrong and you could say okay not that
bad I'll just choose one of the other
three that it gave me but if you can
reverse engineer the way that attackers
now think about it is yeah the LM is GNA
hallucinate generate something that
doesn't exist and as an attacker I'll go
ahead and create all the permutations I
can think of those libraries I'll ahead
of time publish them to different
Registries I'll make them functional
install but put a bag door Trojan or
whatever I want in there and there's
going to be some user at some Enterprise
company installing it uh and at that
point it's like game over I'm like I'm
in their system and you get to be able
to breach a company because AI had
hallucinated something and someone
thought of that before so there's that
risk that exists as well it's a real
risk so would you from that would you
assert that these are the types of
changes that need the most like attended
validation from a human from someone to
actually look at this and say that I
recog you're trying to increase my
supply chain here by pulling in whatever
libraries or tree branch of libraries
and transitors from that this is
something I need to check out myself
always before adding into my project is
that something is that how you look at
this I I so I think it it just it
extends like the surface of what you get
from the llm to something else that you
didn't maybe think maybe you're not like
thinking of it as that important but it
is right so if it gave you like
something very discrete function 10
lines of code and only does is just some
code that you could vet that's fine but
the moment it gives you like hey here's
like a functional application some
serers side API route but I imported
like five different dependences to do
validation to do upload to do whatever
then at that point you're like you're
not just adding some 20 lines of code
you're like literally adding more lines
of code maybe hundreds maybe more
because without talking about any of
them being malicious just the fact that
it really suggested more dependencies so
potential issues like licensing coming
again and it it really just extends and
creates a bigger attack surface because
it extended it from like just completing
code to completing code and giving you a
bigger supply chain security concern
that you now need to be worried about
and honestly it's not just about the
fact whether something there is
malicious or not it could also be the
fact that it's just like literally
outdated or like really badly maintained
so if there's a vulnerability tomorrow
like who maintains the fix for that
you'll get stuck or even if at all you
know about it right there's like a whole
other aspect to it as well so I think
from that aspect it's like a bigger
issue
yeah I know very interesting I want to
get on to the to the deeper dive of this
this episode which is going to be the
part two which will only be on YouTube
and this will be the screen share
version where we actually take a look at
some of these issues and and on a live
demo but before we go while on the
thirdparty library aspect of this and
the supply chain obviously sneakers a
company started off in the open source
security space looking at third party
libraries and so forth with with sneak
open source in terms of using AI or any
kind of ability with an llm here are
there aspects on the open source side in
the vulnerability database and things
like that that make use of AI as well
from the point of view of a vendor using
AI to be more resilient there yeah
definitely I think it's a helpful way to
like label data so like we could use
that if you give it like a cve for
example like a record of vulnerabilities
it's a lot easier to just instead of
reading that line by line going through
the code or whatever it's you could feed
that into an llm and get in right like
what's the CVSs how would impact build
the whole Vector thing classify what's
like the CW that's related to that
potentially build a tree so there's like
different ways which we would use AI to
help us from the vulnerability database
point of view specifically to make it
more I would say trans transient for us
just get the data first from the LM and
then build on to that and trage that but
also I'd like to hear you what you think
the usage perspective to that would be
yeah it's a great question I think um
was a great question I think I asked it
you first right so it must be a great
question yeah no
I think that's an important part and I
think one of the other things which kind
of always struck me is in the
identification of issues in third
parties whereby very often third parties
for whatever reason don't mention that
they fixed a bug or an issue security
issue potentially in their Library
identifying when these issues have been
fixed just a CV hasn't been created for
whatever reason maybe they're not a CNA
maybe they don't know the process to to
create the cve um yeah I think there was
some machine learning style code that
was added to recognize try to find other
examples of similar code changes or
descriptions even in comments and things
like that to identify when you need to
upgrade because there's a security issue
even though the maintainer hasn't
actually acknowledged they fixed a
security issue so you still have
problems in your supply chain that you
need to eliminate but it's just not in a
public list that is addressable from a
tool for example so I think that was
something I always remembered from that
point of view which really helped and I
think it's been in it from from the
early stages of sneak as well yeah
that's been super helpful too that's a
good point yeah yeah which I think it I
used to remember the stat but I think in
the node space specifically or the
JavaScript space rather the vast
majority were like that right the vast
majority of issues vulnerabilities
weren't added to the public CBE database
they were actually just fixed without a
CB being created and so it was one of
the really important things to get a
kind of more of these more carefully
curated databases to get that level of
depth I think in in in hindsight also I
don't know how much people are like a
over aware of the cve crisis for in the
security space but there's a whole cve
crisis where there's like organizations
that handle the reporting or like the
handling of cve reports like of like
security disclosures and they've been
like massively underst staffed with like
thousands of vulnerabilities of like
backlog that they have to fill through
and so what's happening now is that
there's potential like a ton of
applications or dependent third party
components whatever you want in
different aspects depending where you're
like using it but they're like
vulnerable and potentially no one knows
about it so in hindsight I think
investing like sneak investing in this
like trying to catch also unlisted CV is
those that are like you said they just
happen in like a repo someone reports
them the analer fixes them that's it
like they didn't even know what the CV
is right it's are just developers sneak
catching that and saying oh no that's
not just some commit fixing a bu that's
like literally a commit fixing a
security issue and we can pinpoint like
the version that was that is is now
super super helpful to have that
information and that in database yeah
absolutely and of course we should be
mindful as well that it's just the same
things that an attacker can do and and
and identify those types of issues and
and they recognize the window between
that being created and a CV being raised
uh as as as time when they can actually
perform attacks on that uh without
expecting organizations to be rushing to
fix those types of issues in their stack
the ram we could talk about this for a
long time and let's try and keep this to
an episode under a day yeah let's jump
into the into the demo straight after
this but for now for this part of the
episode for those who are listening not
on YouTube we'll say thank you very much
for listening and a big thank you to Lan
for joining us today and yeah tune in
the YouTube part of this session as well
and we'll go into a deep dive and show
you some screen sharing maybe some
vulnerabilities and fixes and things
like that on there as well so lauran
thank you so much for your times and
insights into this very interesting
topic around Ai and security thank you
sonon it's been a
[Music]
[Applause]
pleasure thanks for tuning in join us
next time on the AI native Dev brought
to you by Tesla